## **Asir Intesar Ibne Zaman**

I am a positive and diligent individual with strong organizational skills and exceptional interpersonal abilities. As a passionate data driven product enthusiast, I excel at collecting, validating, and modeling datasets to optimize product performance. I have a knack for market research, feature analysis, and identifying valuable patterns. With a strong belief in the power of determination, I continuously strive for professional growth and achievement of career objectives.



IN		
	•	,

+880 1953608315



asirintesar97@gmail.com



https://asirintesar.github.io/



www.linkedin.com/in/asirintesar/



https://github.com/AsirIntesar



www.behance.net/asirzaman



https://medium.com/@asirintesar97

# Skills & Expertise

#### **Hard Skills**

- Tools & Technologies: PowerBI, Tableau, Adobe XD, Figma, Rstudio, Spreadsheet, Jira, Google Analytics, Microsoft Office, Google Data Studio.
- Industrial Knowledge: Product Management, Data Analysis, UIUX Design, Machine Learning, Agile Methodolies, Software Testing.
- Language: Python, R, C, C++
- Database: Mysql, Microsoft SQL Server, BigQuery

#### **Soft Skills**

- Strong Analytical Ability
- Complex Problem Solving
- Presentation Skills
- Attentive to Detail
- Collaboration



# Education

Institute	Department	Grade	Year
American International University-Bangladesh	Computer Science and Engineering	3.46/4.00	2018-2021
Dhaka City College	Science	5.00/5.00	2014-2016
Motijheel Govt Boys High School	Science	5.00/5.00	2005-2014



# **Work Experience**

<b>BdJobs Limited</b>	Product Analyst	Oct 2022 – Present
AdPlay Technology	Product Executive	Jan 2022 – Sep 2022
ShopUp	Operation Analyst (Intern)	Nov 2021 – Jan 2022



# Projects

- COVID Situation Analysis (Excel, SQL Server, Python, Tableau)
  - Using SQL and Tableau, analyzed COVID-19 dataset up to July 21, situation before and after vaccination, and the fatality ratio.
- Game Sales Analysis (Excel, PowerBI)
  - Dataset with 19k data been cleaned and optimized. Used powerBI for manipulation. Made intuitive dashboard.
- Movie Revenue Prediction (Pandas, Matplotlib, Scikit-Learn)
  - Predicted the success rate based on the type and budget comparing with an online movie dataset using Naïve Bias Classifier
- **Housing Prices Prediction** (Kaggle Competition on ML)
  - Predicted house pricing based on the area, house size and facilities. Used online dataset. Random Forest and, Decision Tree algorithm been implemented)
- Bangladesh Crime Analysis (Excel, PowerBI)
  - Using Kaggle dataset on crime record of Bangladesh, answered some self-raised questions on powerbi.

## Languages

- Bangla | Native
- > English | Fluent

### **Extra-Curricular & Volunteer**

- AIUB Photography Club | Photographer & Event Organizer
  - 2020-Present (Organized an event)
- Rekindle | Distribution volunteer, Ramadan Bliss
  - 2019 (Lead a distributor team, Developed networking skill)
- Finalist | MGBHS Interschool Photo Exhibition
  - 2018 (Became rewarded for the mobile photography position)

#### Personal Interest

- Travelling (Travel vlogs in YouTube channel)
- Cycling (Got souvenir for the ride on 16th December)
- Designing (Freelanced App and Website designer)
- Photography (Finalist of 2 photo exhibitions)
- Aqua scaping (Experienced in Planted and Community Tank)
- Writing (Blog writing on cricket analysis)



**1 June 2020-Ongoing** Shoplifting Detection using Transfer

Learning

15 Aug 2020 – 30 May 2021 Undergrad Thesis on Suspicious Human

**Action Recognition** 



### Become a Product Manager | Udemy

- Definition of Product Managers, Product managers roles and responsibilities.
- Types of Product Manager (B2B, B2C, C2C) and their behavior.
- Phases of Product lifecycle.
- Product management frameworks and development processes.
- Market research, Competitor analysis.
- MVP (Minimum viable product) and its workflow.
- Wireframing and collaboration with other teams.
- Interviews tips and tricks and self-evaluation as a product manager.

### Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

- Foundation of Data analysis, The 5 Why rule.
- Understanding context, Data strategy, SMART question rule Asking the right questions for making data-driven decisions.
- Data ethics, Types of data, Schema, Meta data, Data model,
  Dealing with unexpected office situation.
- Data integrity, Hypothesis testing, Random Sampling, Margin of Errors, Data Processing, Query Writing, SQL and BigQuery.
- BigQuery, VLOOKUP, Aggregation, Nested query.
- Tableau Dashboard, Creating VIZ, Data Storytelling.
- R Coding, Visualization, Markdown, Report making in R.
- Portfolio building, Data analyst Mock interview, Case study.

#### Emotional Intelligence | Bohubrihi

• Empathy, Understanding the timing of question asking, Skill of Mind reading. Self-Development skill.



#### **Shafi Mohammad Wasif Osman**

GM, Business Intelligence Robi Axiata Limited Email: smwosman@gmail.com

#### Andalib Hasan

Operations Director Foodpanda Email: andalib14@gmail.com